BENJAMIN GAMBLING

#: +1 604-905-9464

Email: benjamin.gambling@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/benjamin-gamblinggithub.io/

PROFILE

I'm a self-taught full-stack web developer with a professional history in computational structural dynamics and guest experience. Specialising in JavaScript I have developer a strong portfolio of responsive and visually pleasing web applications using modern technologies, test driven development, object orientated design and all with a focus on writing clean, elegant and efficient code.

EDUCATION

2020 - NOW THE ODIN PROJECT / FREE CODE CAMP / HARVARD CS50

Using multiple online resources to educate myself in web development, I created a number of personal projects along side tutorials and coursework to reinforce what I had learnt. Aligning the curriculums to gain a deeper understanding of programming concepts and adapt to different styles of learning and preferences to find what worked well for me.

2010-2014 UNIVERSITY OF SHEFFIELD - MENG CIVIL & STRUCTURAL ENGINEERING

Specialising in structural dynamics in high stress situations, mainly highrise structures under blast, fire and seismic loads. My final year project involved modelling steel framed structures under high temperature loadings. Receiving a final grade of 2:1 with honours.

EXPERIENCE

2016 - 2020 VAIL RESORTS - PRODUCT SALES & SERVICES SUPERVISOR

Working in number of roles within the product sales and services team in both Falls Creek, Australia and Whistler, Canada, I have overseen large teams of seasonal employees who are required to sell products and provide exceptional guest service. I have played a huge part in the testing and integration of a new point of sales system, which was produced in house and is continuously being developed. As the largest resort it is vital that both the guests and employees have a smooth user experience with our online and in resort sales systems. Providing in-depth training, constant development and online resources through our intranet as well as a constant front line presence to assist however it was needed.

2014 - 2016 TPS CONSULT - BLAST ENGINEER

Recruited straight out of university for my masters work involving the dynamic effects on buildings in disastrous circumstances. The job consisted of work winning, project/account management, researching potential clients and working within large teams of multi-disciplinary and multi-national personnel. The engineering side consisted of a range of different roles such blast engineering, structural analysis and design, counter terrorism measures , hostile vehicle mitigation and explosive safety. I also was invalided with the structural engineering team where I developed some tools and strategies to create efficient pad foundation design.

LANGUAGES / FRAMEWORKS

Front-End

- JavaScript (ES6 +)
- HTML5
- CSS3/SASS
- React
- Bootstrap
- Webpack
- D3.js

Back-End

- Node.js
- Express.js

SQL/NoSQL

- TSQL/SQLite
- MongoDB w/ Mongoose
- Firebase

Test Driven Development

- Jest/Jasmine/Chai

Cloud Platforms

- Heroku
- Firebase

Version Control

- Git
- Github

Structural

- MATLAB/ MathLAB
- Fortran
- Visual Basics

SKILLS

- Problem solving
- Critical thinking
- Object-orientated design
- Working with modern technologies
- Leadership/Teamwork
- Adaptability